export const chapter = "Chapter - 31: Marginalisation  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the main cause of inequality mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Differences in physical appearance",
        optionB: "Economic, social, and cultural factors",
        optionC: "Religious beliefs",
        correctAnswer: "B) Economic, social, and cultural factors",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the meaning of 'marginalisation' in the context of the text?",
        optionA: "Being at the center of society",
        optionB: "Exclusion from the mainstream",
        optionC: "Having a distinct cultural identity",
        correctAnswer: "B) Exclusion from the mainstream",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary factor that leads to marginalization in some communities?",
        optionA: "Unique habits and customs",
        optionB: "Economic disparities",
        optionC: "Educational qualifications",
        correctAnswer: "A) Unique habits and customs",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which groups are considered as marginalised communities in the text?",
        optionA: "Scheduled Castes (SC) and Scheduled Tribes (ST)",
        optionB:
          "Economically Weaker Section (EWS) and Other Backward Classes (OBC)",
        optionC: "All religious minorities",
        correctAnswer: "A) Scheduled Castes (SC) and Scheduled Tribes (ST)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the key characteristic of Scheduled Castes (SC) mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Forced to adopt specific occupations",
        optionB: "High social and economic status",
        optionC: "Engaged in diverse professions",
        correctAnswer: "A) Forced to adopt specific occupations",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did the British do to many Scheduled Tribes in India during their occupation?",
        optionA: "Provided them with better living conditions",
        optionB: "Expelled them from forests for resource exploitation",
        optionC: "Granted them special privileges",
        correctAnswer:
          "B) Expelled them from forests for resource exploitation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who are considered as Other Backward Classes (OBC) in the text?",
        optionA: "Economically prosperous communities",
        optionB: "Politically influential groups",
        optionC: "Socially and economically underdeveloped groups",
        correctAnswer: "C) Socially and economically underdeveloped groups",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which group is given a 10% reservation in admission to educational institutions and government employment from 2019?",
        optionA: "Scheduled Castes (SC)",
        optionB: "Economically Weaker Section (EWS)",
        optionC: "Minorities",
        correctAnswer: "B) Economically Weaker Section (EWS)",
      },
      {
        question: "How are minority communities defined in the text?",
        optionA: "Based on population size",
        optionB: "Based on religious or linguistic criteria",
        optionC: "Based on political influence",
        correctAnswer: "B) Based on religious or linguistic criteria",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which social reformer is mentioned in the text as working to eradicate untouchability and discrimination against marginalised classes?",
        optionA: "Mahatma Gandhi",
        optionB: "Narendra Modi",
        optionC: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        correctAnswer: "A) Mahatma Gandhi",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Inequality stems from several factors, such as some are __________ and others are poor, some are considered high-caste, and others are considered low-caste.",
        options: ["rich", "educated", "discriminated"],
        answer: "rich",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Marginalisation can be due to economic, social, cultural, religious, educational, or __________ factors.",
        options: ["political", "legal", "geographical"],
        answer: "political",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Scheduled Tribes (ST) are also called Adivasis, which means __________ or original people.",
        options: ["primitive", "modern", "indigenous"],
        answer: "primitive",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Constitution has recognized Scheduled Tribes (ST) and has made several legal provisions for their __________, social, and economic uplift.",
        options: ["educational", "political", "cultural"],
        answer: "cultural",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In addition to the members of the Scheduled Castes and the Scheduled Tribes, there are several other groups recognized as __________.",
        options: [
          "Economically Weaker Section (EWS)",
          "Other Backward Classes (OBC)",
          "religious minorities",
        ],
        answer: "Other Backward Classes (OBC)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has provided a 10% reservation in admission to educational institutions and government employment for the __________ category.",
        options: [
          "Scheduled Castes (SC)",
          "Economically Weaker Section (EWS)",
          "Scheduled Tribes (ST)",
        ],
        answer: "Economically Weaker Section (EWS)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The word 'minority' signifies 'a group which is less numerous' based on __________ or language.",
        options: ["size", "religion", "ethnicity"],
        answer: "religion",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government runs several welfare measures for these minority communities, including scholarships, fellowships, and other __________ for their development.",
        options: ["programs", "punishments", "restrictions"],
        answer: "programs",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Many social reformers have worked to eradicate untouchability and discrimination against the marginalised classes, including Jotiba Phule, Dr. B.R. Ambedkar, and __________.",
        options: [
          "Jawaharlal Nehru",
          "Mahatma Gandhi",
          "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        ],
        answer: "Mahatma Gandhi",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Despite the law declaring manual scavenging illegal, it continues to be forced upon the depressed classes, and they face severe discrimination, even from other depressed classes. The above law prescribes an imprisonment for up to one year and/or a fine of Rs 2,000 for an offender, who can also be liable to prosecution under the Scheduled Castes and Scheduled Tribes (Prevention of Atrocities) Act, 1989. The Supreme Court too has directed every department/ministry of central and state governments to indicate a time-bound program for liberating and rehabilitating all manual scavengers. Still, manual scavenging continues to exist. People need to be made aware of the pitiable condition so that this abominable practice can be abolished altogether.\nIn the provided text, please fill in the blank with the correct term: '_________________ laws' (plural).",
        options: ["Caste-based", "Discriminatory", "Manual scavenging"],
        answer: "Caste-based",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Marginalization is solely based on physical appearance.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Economic, social, and cultural factors are some of the causes of marginalization.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Scheduled Castes (SC) are considered a privileged group.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Scheduled Tribes (ST) are also known as Adivasis.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government has not provided any reservation for Economically Weaker Sections (EWS) in educational institutions and government employment.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Minority communities are defined solely based on population size.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The police cannot refuse to file an FIR under any circumstances.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The judge in a criminal case decides a case based on personal beliefs.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Social reformers have played no role in eradicating untouchability and discrimination against marginalized classes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Manual scavenging has been completely eradicated in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
